<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0"><channel><title><![CDATA[Main]]></title><description><![CDATA[Obsidian digital garden]]></description><link>http://github.com/dylang/node-rss</link><image><url>lib\media\favicon.png</url><title>Main</title><link></link></image><generator>Webpage HTML Export plugin for Obsidian</generator><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 20:30:40 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="lib\rss.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 20:30:39 GMT</pubDate><ttl>60</ttl><dc:creator></dc:creator><item><title><![CDATA[Illegal Arms Trade Iran]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://en.mehrnews.com/news/216675/Iran-urges-holistic-approach-to-deal-with-illegal-arms-trade" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://en.mehrnews.com/news/216675/Iran-urges-holistic-approach-to-deal-with-illegal-arms-trade" target="_blank">Article</a><br>
"Facilitating a non-discriminatory transfer of technology and equipment necessary to combat illicit trade and trafficking in SALWs to developing countries—such as x-ray machines, full-body scanners, advanced border control radars, etc., is urgent for strengthening Member States' capabilities for effectively implementing the POA.<br>Unfortunately, unlawful restrictions imposed on Iran, contrary to the commitments made in the UN Programme of Action, have limited our access to the technical and technological assistance necessary for combating the illicit trade of small arms and light weapons in the region."<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://unoda-poa.s3.amazonaws.com/poa-reports-le/2016%4092%402016%20-%20PoA%20-%20Iran%20-%20E.pdf" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://unoda-poa.s3.amazonaws.com/poa-reports-le/2016%4092%402016%20-%20PoA%20-%20Iran%20-%20E.pdf" target="_blank">UNPoA 2016 Iran Assesment</a>]]></description><link>model-un\illegal-arms-trade\illegal-arms-trade-iran.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Model UN/Illegal Arms Trade/Illegal Arms Trade Iran.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 22:32:55 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran Opening Speech SALWs]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Clash<br>
Continue to fight against illegal arms trade<br>Information<br>
idk<br>Call to Action<br>
lift restrictions on Iran and reinforce Un programme of Action (UNPoA)<br>Speech<br>
Honorable chair and esteemed delegates,<br>The Islamic Republic of Iran is in favor of the fight on illicit weapons trade, but condemns the creation of any new programs, policies, or restrictions other than the UN Program of Action on small arms and light weapons (SALW). Iran vows to tackle problems collaboratively outlined by the UNPoA, instead of expanding the scope of the issue and creating more on the way.<br>Iran has demonstrated its concern on the issue both Locally and Internationally. In 2015 Iran implemented the fourth national plan for combatting arms trafficking with which border security improved and the inspecting of arms storage became more frequent. Between 2015-2016 Iran has held meetings of the joint security committee with China, Turkey, and, Armenia. <br>Iran proposes to send equipment such as x-rays and various radars to developing countries in order to help combat the illegal arms trade where technology is insufficient.  Unfortunately these actions are hard for Iran to carry out due the vast sanctions imposed by western nations, so Iran hopes for the cooperation of the United Nations to improve living conditions around the world. ]]></description><link>model-un\illegal-arms-trade\iran-opening-speech-salws.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Model UN/Illegal Arms Trade/Iran Opening Speech SALWs.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 16:48:44 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[temp]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Hello! We're excited to share insights from a recent statement by Iran at the Fourth Review Conference on the UN Programme of Action to combat the illicit trade in small arms and light weapons. Iran emphasizes the importance of a comprehensive approach to tackle this pressing issue and expresses its commitment to supporting a consensus on the UN Action Plan. Together, we can work towards a safer world!<br>Example Questions:<br>What specific actions does Iran propose to support the UN Action Plan on small arms and light weapons?<br>
How does Iran's position align with the statements made by other countries at the conference?<br>What are the key objectives of the UN Programme of Action on the Illicit Trade in Small Arms and Light Weapons?
<br>What specific actions does Iran propose to support the UN Action Plan on small arms and light weapons?<br>
AvatarLogo<br>
CopyIcon<br>Iran proposes several specific actions to support the UN Action Plan on small arms and light weapons, including:<br>Holistic Approach: Iran emphasizes the need for a comprehensive approach to address the root causes of the illicit trade in small arms and light weapons, which includes tackling organized crime and drug trafficking linked to this trade (Page 2).

International Cooperation and Assistance: Iran highlights the importance of enhancing international cooperation and assistance, particularly in providing financial support, technical assistance, and technology transfer to developing countries. This is crucial for effectively combating the illicit trade (Page 4), (Page 5).

Access to Technology: Iran advocates for facilitating a non-discriminatory transfer of technology and equipment necessary for combating illicit trade, such as advanced border control technologies (Page 2).

Implementation of the Fellowship Programme: Iran supports the expedited implementation of the United Nations Fellowship Programme on Small Arms and Light Weapons, which aims to address the technical knowledge and expertise gaps in developing countries (Page 5).

Bilateral and Trilateral Agreements: Iran has established agreements with several countries in the region to prevent and combat the illicit trade in small arms and light weapons, focusing on regional cooperation (Page 2).

Focus on Existing Frameworks: Iran calls for refining the implementation of the UN Programme of Action and its International Tracing Instrument, rather than introducing new elements that could complicate the existing framework (Page 4).
<br>These actions reflect Iran's commitment to not only addressing the challenges posed by the illicit trade in small arms but also to fostering international collaboration to enhance security and stability.<br>How does Iran's position align with the statements made by other countries at the conference?<br>
AvatarLogo<br>
CopyIcon<br>Iran's position aligns with the statements made by other countries at the conference in several key ways:<br>Emphasis on International Cooperation: Like many other nations, Iran stresses the importance of international cooperation and assistance in combating the illicit trade in small arms and light weapons. This is a common theme among various delegations, highlighting the need for collective efforts to address the challenges posed by this trade (Page 4), (Page 5).

Support for Existing Frameworks: Iran advocates for refining the implementation of the UN Programme of Action (UNPoA) and its International Tracing Instrument (ITI), which resonates with the sentiments of other countries that prioritize strengthening existing frameworks rather than introducing new, potentially complicating elements (Page 4). Many delegations have echoed the need to focus on practical solutions within the established guidelines.

Call for Technology Transfer: Iran's call for facilitating access to technology and equipment for developing countries aligns with the broader consensus among many nations that emphasize the need for capacity building and technological support to effectively combat illicit arms trade (Page 2), (Page 1). This reflects a shared understanding of the challenges faced by developing countries in this area.

Focus on Root Causes: Iran's approach to addressing the root causes of illicit arms trade, such as organized crime and drug trafficking, is consistent with the views of other countries that recognize the multifaceted nature of the issue. Many delegations have highlighted the importance of addressing these underlying factors to achieve long-term solutions (Page 2).

Commitment to Consensus: Iran expresses its readiness to support a consensus outcome document for the conference, which aligns with the collaborative spirit emphasized by other countries. This reflects a collective desire to work together towards effective implementation of the UNPoA (Page 1).
<br>Overall, Iran's position is in harmony with the broader discussions at the conference, focusing on cooperation, practical implementation, and addressing the root causes of the illicit trade in small arms and light weapons.<br>How does Iran's position differ with the statements made by other countries at the conference?<br>
AvatarLogo<br>
CopyIcon<br>Iran's position at the conference differs from the statements made by other countries in several notable ways:<br>Sovereignty and Non-Interference: Iran emphasizes the sovereign right of each state to decide which international instruments to join and expresses skepticism about linking the implementation of the UN Programme of Action (UNPoA) with other non-consensual documents, such as the Arms Trade Treaty and the Firearms Protocol. This contrasts with some countries that advocate for a more integrated approach, suggesting that linking these frameworks could enhance overall effectiveness (Page 5).

Rejection of External Allegations: Iran categorically rejects allegations regarding its involvement in arms transfers that violate international law, asserting that it has not engaged in any activities contrary to its international obligations. This stance may differ from other countries that have raised concerns about Iran's role in regional conflicts and arms proliferation, reflecting a divergence in perspectives on accountability and compliance with international norms (Page 6).

Focus on Existing Frameworks: While many countries may support the introduction of new measures or frameworks to address the illicit arms trade, Iran advocates for a more cautious approach, urging a focus on refining and effectively implementing existing frameworks rather than expanding the scope with new concepts. This reflects a more conservative stance compared to those advocating for ambitious new initiatives (Page 4), (Page 5).

Concerns Over External Restrictions: Iran highlights the impact of unlawful restrictions imposed on it, which it claims hinder its ability to access necessary technical and technological assistance for combating illicit arms trade. This perspective may not be as prominently featured by other countries, which may focus more on collective challenges rather than specific national grievances (Page 2).

Pragmatic Recommendations: Iran calls for practical recommendations to address implementation challenges, emphasizing the need to focus on immediate, actionable solutions rather than theoretical discussions. This pragmatic approach may contrast with other delegations that might prioritize broader discussions on policy frameworks or theoretical underpinnings of arms control (Page 5), (Page 3).
<br>In summary, while Iran shares common ground with many countries on the need for cooperation and effective implementation of the UNPoA, its emphasis on sovereignty, rejection of external allegations, focus on existing frameworks, and specific national concerns set it apart from the positions of other nations at the conference.<br>Condense this speech into 1 minute<br>
AvatarLogo<br>
CopyIcon<br>Madam President, esteemed delegates,<br>The Islamic Republic of Iran is committed to fully implementing the UN Programme of Action on the Illicit Trade in Small Arms and Light Weapons. We advocate for a holistic approach that addresses the root causes of this issue, including organized crime and drug trafficking.<br>International cooperation and assistance are crucial, particularly in providing financial and technological support to developing countries. We emphasize the need for a non-discriminatory transfer of technology to enhance capabilities in combating illicit arms trade.<br>Iran firmly believes in refining existing frameworks like the UNPoA and its International Tracing Instrument, rather than introducing new elements that could complicate our efforts. We reject any allegations regarding our compliance with international law and assert our right to sovereignty in deciding which international instruments to join.<br>In conclusion, we stand ready to support a consensus outcome document and work collaboratively towards effective implementation of the UN Action Plan. Thank you.]]></description><link>model-un\illegal-arms-trade\temp.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Model UN/Illegal Arms Trade/temp.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 18:10:11 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Iran Opening Speech Ukraine War]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>Iran acknowledges the dangerous situation in Ukraine. Iran wants to motion the assembly towards achieving peace  ]]></description><link>model-un\ukraine-war\iran-opening-speech-ukraine-war.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Model UN/Ukraine War/Iran Opening Speech Ukraine War.md</guid><pubDate>Mon, 04 Nov 2024 21:26:41 GMT</pubDate></item><item><title><![CDATA[Ukraine War Iran]]></title><description><![CDATA[ 
 <br>
<br>
**What role have recent economic sanctions had on Russia and the global economy?  

<br>Sanctions are placed not by the UN 
<br>Placed by western nations in order to weaken Russia  
<br>Russian economy is experiencing more growth than other European countries 

<br><a rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.bbc.com/news/business-68823399" target="_blank">https://www.bbc.com/news/business-68823399</a> 
<br>*Russia to grow faster than all advanced economies says IMF 
<br>Away from Russia, the IMF downgraded its forecasts across Europe and for the UK this year, predicting 0.5% growth this year, making the UK the second weakest performer across the G7 group of advanced economies, behind Germany.
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.imf.org/external/datamapper/PPPSH@WEO/OEMDC/ADVEC/WEOWORLD" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.imf.org/external/datamapper/PPPSH@WEO/OEMDC/ADVEC/WEOWORLD" target="_blank">PPP List IMF</a>


<br>USA
<br>China
<br>India
<br>Russia 
<br>Japan
<br>Germany




<br>
**What are the humanitarian consequences of the war on civilians?  

<br>Ukraine is experiencing a Humanitarian crisis

<br>UNHCR - 6 million refugees
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/ukraines-population-has-fallen-by-10-million-since-russias-invasion-un-says-2024-10-22/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.reuters.com/world/europe/ukraines-population-has-fallen-by-10-million-since-russias-invasion-un-says-2024-10-22/" target="_blank">Reuters Ukraine Population</a> all time low fertility rate, population down 10 million


<br>Many killed  

<br>Ukraine: 150,000 - 500,000 Deaths &amp; Injuries
<br>Russia: 400,00 - 700,000 Deaths &amp; Injuries


<br>Nation Wide conscription (many cases of taking un prepared men) 

<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/10/28/conscription-ukraine-military-men-russia-war/" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://foreignpolicy.com/2024/10/28/conscription-ukraine-military-men-russia-war/" target="_blank">Foreign Policy Ukraine Conscription</a> Corruption common to fake a medical disability
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/10/15/to-boost-ukraines-army-feared-patrols-hunt-for-potential-conscripts" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.aljazeera.com/features/2024/10/15/to-boost-ukraines-army-feared-patrols-hunt-for-potential-conscripts" target="_blank">ALJAZEERA Conscription</a> Violence in conscription offices
<br><a data-tooltip-position="top" aria-label="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/russia-ukraine-war-conscription-raid-1.7351297" rel="noopener nofollow" class="external-link" href="https://www.cbc.ca/news/world/russia-ukraine-war-conscription-raid-1.7351297" target="_blank">CBC Conscription</a> Recruiters raid Bar for legible men


<br>Terrible economic state (foreign aid used for government payouts, fighting men not receiving compensations, as well as families with casualties.  


<br>
**Are there any other ways to promote peace and security in Ukraine without armed conflict?  

<br>PEACE TALKS!  
<br>June 2024 Ukraine peace summit was conducted without Russia, or China


]]></description><link>model-un\ukraine-war\ukraine-war-iran.html</link><guid isPermaLink="false">Model UN/Ukraine War/Ukraine War Iran.md</guid><pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 17:05:22 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>